Adam Tilly

Forest Lake, MN
Phone: (612)236-6092
Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/adam-tilly-04250866/
Tillyjadam@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/Tilly52mn. Portfolio: https://tilly52mn.github.io/react-portfolio/

Summary

Full stack web developer utilizing a career of problem solving in the field mechanical engineering to create applications that have an enjoyable user experience. Received a certificate through a University of Minnesota coding boot camp, developing technologies such as MERN, SQL, Git, Rest, Heroku and more. Skilled communicator, enjoy solving problems, and team player.

Education

University of Minnesota Bootcamp

Feb. 2022

• Full Stack Web Development, Grade: -A 91.9%

North Dakota State University

Dec. 2013

• Mechanical Engineering, Bachelor of Science Degree

Computer Skills

Language: JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Databases: MongoDB, MySQL

Related Technologies: Visual Studio Code(free version), SQL Workbench, Postman, Insomnia, React, Express.js, Node.js, JSON, MySQL, Progressive Web Applications, JQuery, Bootstrap, Responsive Design, Object Orientated Programing(using JavaScript), REST, CRUD, APIs, Local Storage, Session Storage

Projects

Connect-4 | https://cbc-connect-4.herokuapp.com/ | https://github.com/Bycicleace/connect-four

Created web app to play connect-4

Role: Front end JSX & set up react and more

Tools: MERN, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Social Media API | https://github.com/Tilly52mn/Social_Network_Comment_API

Created to allow users to have thoughts, reactions and friends. Made as class assignment.

Role: Sole author

Tools: Node.js, Mongoose, Mongo DB, Express

Experience

Rosenbauer Minnesota, Design Engineer

5181 260th St, Wyoming MN 55092

Aug. 2021- Current

Responsible for the design of all components on a firetruck body

• Updated excel spreadsheet for calculating firetrucks weights and how they are balanced

Applied Engineering Inc, Design Engineer II

June 2019-Aug. 2021

7077 Northland Circle North, Suite 110, Brooklyn Park, MN 55428

Assisted customers in their design engineering needs

- Assist a design team in reverse engineering an electrical connector product line and also designing production fixtures to assist in assembling the connectors.
- Designed mechanical components for automated assembly machines
- Created a crane frame model in Solidworks for seismic FEA testing to be done.

Rosenbauer Minnesota

5181 260th St, Wyoming MN 55092

Design Engineer

June 2018- June 2019

Responsible for the design of piece parts on a firetruck body and ordering special parts

Bill of Material Specialist

Feb. 2015-June 2018

Created Bills of Materials for firetrucks based on specifications given by the customer and also special projects.

- Participated in a Leadership Development Program (2018)
- Responsible for \$100,000+ worth of parts order per firetruck daily

RFA Engineering, Engineer I

Jan. 2014-Feb. 2015

12986 Valley View Road, Eden Prairie, MN 55344

Designed wire harness routing, air systems for large commercial engine applications and hydraulic routings on surface drills for Caterpillar Additional Experiences
 Board Member - Non Profit Mind Over Matter, Member at Large- Church Council Other Interests Golf, Running, Computers, Bowling, Biking, Softball, Hiking, Skiing, Fishing